我很高兴为您介绍这个由Sharon Zhou教授的扩散模型短期课程。
I'm thrilled to present to you this short course on diffusion models taught by Sharon Zhou.
在旅程中途，稳定扩散、DALL-E等等能够仅通过一个提示生成图像，有时甚至是美丽的图像。
Mid-journey, stable diffusion, DALL-E, and others are able to generate an image, sometimes a beautiful image, given only a prompt.
这些算法是如何工作的？
How do these algorithms work?
你可能听过这些算法学会减去噪声来生成图像的模糊描述，
You may have heard of a vague description of these algorithms learning to subtract noise to generate an image,
但在这个短期课程中，Sharon将带领你了解使用扩散模型进行图像生成的具体实现，
but in this short course, Sharon will step you through a concrete implementation of image generation using a diffusion model
这样你就能明白它究竟是如何工作的。
so that you understand the technical details of exactly how it works.
太酷了，谢谢Andrew。
Cool, thanks Andrew.
在这门课程中，你将了解到目前扩散模型的现状和能力。
In this course, you'll be learning about the current state and capabilities of diffusion models used today.
你将从了解采样过程开始，从纯噪声开始，逐步优化，最终获得一个好看的图像。
You'll start by understanding the sampling process, starting with pure noise and progressively refining it to obtain a final nice-looking image.
你将学会训练扩散模型所需的编程技能。
You'll build the necessary programming skills to train a diffusion model effectively.
你将学会如何构建一个能预测图像中噪声的神经网络。
You'll learn how to build a neural network that can predict noise in an image.
你将为模型添加上下文，以便你可以控制想要生成的内容。
You'll add context to the model so that you can control what you want it to generate.
最后，通过实现先进的算法，你将学会如何将采样过程加速10倍。
And finally, by implementing advanced algorithms, you'll learn how to accelerate the sampling process by a factor of 10.
这是一个中级到高级的课程。
This is an intermediate to advanced course.
我们假设你熟悉Python和基本的神经网络训练。
We assume you're familiar with Python and basic neural network training.
所以举个例子，我们会假设你知道什么是反向传播。
So for example, we'll assume you know what backpropagation is.
我们将在整个过程中使用PyTorch。
We'll use PyTorch throughout.
但是，如果你熟悉其他机器学习框架，如TensorFlow，你应该也能跟上进度。
But if you're familiar with other machine learning frameworks, such as TensorFlow, you should be able to follow along just fine.
因此，我们在这个短期课程中使用的实例将是生成16x16的像素精灵，就像那些用在视频游戏中的小8位角色。
And so the running example we'll use for this short course will be generating 16 by 16 sprites, like those little 8-bit characters used in video games.
我们选择这个例子是为了让你不仅能浏览笔记本，
We chose this example so that it's feasible for you to not just go through the notebooks,
还能亲自运行它们，以便在Jupyter笔记本中生成可爱的像素精灵。
but also run them yourself to generate cute sprites yourself right there in that Jupyter Notebook.
扩散模型正成为生命科学等领域尖端研究的基础。
Diffusion models are becoming a foundation for cutting-edge research in the life sciences and other sectors too.
比如，生成用于药物发现的分子。
For example, generating molecules for drug discovery.
所以，当你理解扩散模型的技术细节时，
So when you understand the technical details of diffusion models,
你也会更好地理解并可能自己应用这些模型。
you'll also be in a better position to understand and perhaps apply such models yourself.
很多人共同努力创建了这个短期课程。
Many people worked together to build this short course.
我要感谢Aaron Lou和Mehmet Giray Ogut的重要贡献。
I want to thank Aaron Lou and Mehmet Giray Ogut for their significant contributions.
还有在DeepLearning.ai网站上的Geoff Ladwig和Eddy Shyu。
And on the DeepLearning.ai site, also Geoff Ladwig and Eddy Shyu.
那么，让我把时间交给Sharon，希望你们喜欢这门课程。
So with that, let me hand it over to Sharon, and I hope you enjoy the course.
太好了。
Great.
我们开始吧。
Let's get started.